<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on PHI 162</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on PHI 162</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 20:14:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Topic 3: Evolution and Ethics</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/evolution-and-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 12:11:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/evolution-and-ethics/</guid>
      <description>Reading  Wilson, E. O. 1975. Sociobiology: The New Synthesis. short excerpt distributed in class. Kitcher, Philip. 1993. “Four Ways of &amp;lsquo;Biologicizing&amp;rsquo; Ethics.” In In Mendel&amp;rsquo;s mirror: philosophical reflections on biology. Oxford University Press, 2003. Find the eBook through Axinn Library here.  Reading questions  What does Wilson think the relationship between philosophical ethics and evolutionary biology should be? What reasons does he offer in favor of that relationship? What four kinds of relationships between evolutionary biology and philosophical ethics does Kitcher think might be embraced by someone like Wilson?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2: Darwin and Natural Selection</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/darwin-and-natural-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 16:57:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/darwin-and-natural-selection/</guid>
      <description>Reading  Darwin, Charles. 1859. The Origin of Species. First edition (of 6). Read Chapter 3. Then, read just up to page 10 in Chapter 4, and finally the final paragraph of Chapter 14 (on the last page). Available via Blackboard. Waters, C. Kenneth. 2003. “The Arguments in the Origin of Species.” In The Cambridge Companion to Darwin, edited by Gregory Radick and Jonathan Hodge, 116–139. Cambridge University Press. via Blackboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1: Before Natural Selection</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/before-natural-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 16:56:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/before-natural-selection/</guid>
      <description>Reading  Aristotle, excerpts from Physics and Parts of Animals (about 350 BCE). Handout. Available through Blackboard &amp;gt; Course Documents.  Note: This is short but dense. Try to work through it carefully; see the reading questions below ↓.   William Smellie, “Of the Progressive Scale or Chain of Beings in the Universe” (1791). Available through Blackboard &amp;gt; Course Documents.  Note: This is an account of the relationships among all living things from the perspective of late-eighteenth century biology in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/assignments/assignment-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 21:19:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/assignments/assignment-2/</guid>
      <description>This content will be available later in the course, well before the due date.
See the Writing a Philosophy Paper handout for general guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/assignments/assignment-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 21:19:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/assignments/assignment-1/</guid>
      <description>Choose one of the following, numbered topic-options, below. Focusing on what it asks for, write at least 1200 words. (Adding in response to questions: There is no upper limit for how many words you write, but there is also not any expectation that you will write much more than the minimum.) Each of the topics has two parts, marked “a” and “b.” They are intended to be thought of as equally important, so devote at least 40% of your writing to each of those two parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Test Questions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/notes/second-test-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 09:54:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/notes/second-test-questions/</guid>
      <description>This content will be available later in the course, well before the test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Test Questions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/notes/first-test-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 08:54:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/notes/first-test-questions/</guid>
      <description>Our first test will take place during class on March 16.
How to study To study for the test review and think about the answers to the Learning Questions for each of our units to date, and try to find the main arguments for each of the readings and/or class presentations. Think about integration among the topics — to how they might be understood as answer to the same, more general questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/notes/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 11:44:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/notes/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading.
4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):
   letter 4pt Student’s academic performance …     A 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation Rubric</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/notes/participation-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 11:42:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/notes/participation-rubric/</guid>
      <description>This is the participation rubric to be used for grading participation in this course. Read it as saying “A student who demonstrates … earns a grade of X,” where X is the letter grade at the top of the column.1
   A B C D F     Active role in discussions, drawing on texts Regular, constructive participation drawing on texts Inconsistent constructive participation based on texts Vague comments reflecting limited engagement with texts Persistent lack of engagement with texts   Full preparation for approximately every class Substantial preparation, normally Inconsistent evidence of preparation Rare evidence of participation No positive evidence of participation   Success at advancing level and depth of discussion, persistently Regular contributions based on assigned material, which sometimes improve discussion and never diminish it Rare or no significant contribution to the level of discussion while not reducing it Activity sometimes diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment Activity regularly diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment   Active engagement with and listening to peers, persistently Sincere efforts to interact with peers, normally Limited engagement with peers Rare interaction with peers No interaction with peers      This rubric is significantly based on, and lightly adapted from, one written by another philosophy professor, Jay Odenbaugh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:56:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/resources/</guid>
      <description>Hofstra  Minor in Data Analysis and Scientific Reasoning Philosophy Department  Academic journals  Biology &amp;amp; Philosophy (requires Hofstra log-in) Philosophy, Theory, and Practice in Biology Studies in History and Philosophy of Science (requires Hofstra log-in) Philosophy of Science (requires Hofstra log-in) Journal of the History of Biology (partially paywalled; some articles open access)  Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy articles The SEP is a high-quality, free resource. This is a sampling of just some of its articles on philosophy of biology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
