<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>topics on PHI 162</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/tags/topics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in topics on PHI 162</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 07:17:34 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/tags/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Topic 7: Health and Disease</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/health-and-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 07:17:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/health-and-disease/</guid>
      <description>Reading  Cooper, Rachel. 2002. “Disease.” Studies in History and Philosophy of Science Part C: Studies in History and Philosophy of Biological and Biomedical Sciences. 33(2):263–28.2 https://doi.org/10.1016/S0039-3681(02)00018-3 (or, if you have a problem accessing through that the DOI, try this Hofstra-library link: https://hofstra.on.worldcat.org/oclc/4931258279). Griffiths, Paul E. and John Matthewson. 2018. “Evolution, Dysfunction, and Disease: A Reappraisal.” The British Journal for the Philosophy of Science 69(2): 301–327. (PDF via Axinn Library). Focus on reading section 2 on the “selected effect account” and then look through the next few sections for replies to objections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 6: Animal Minds</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/animal-minds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 09:06:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/animal-minds/</guid>
      <description>Reading  Descartes, René. 1637/1646. “Descartes on the significance of language.” excerpts from Discourse on the Method and a published letter. (Note that the site says the first excerpt is from Descartes&amp;rsquo;s Meditations, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually from the Discourse Part 6. You can see the context of it in the Early Modern Texts version here, where it&amp;rsquo;s on pages 22–23.) Andrews, Kristin. 2020. Sections 4.3–4.6 of &amp;ldquo;Consciousness&amp;rdquo; in The Animal Mind: An Introduction to the Philosophy of Animal Cognition Second Edition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 5: Biological Information</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/biological-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 18:26:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/biological-information/</guid>
      <description>Do genes function by carrying information, like blueprints for builders? Do they say things?
Reading  Godfrey-Smith, Peter. 2013. “Information,” Chapter 9 of Philosophy of Biology. Princeton University Press. eBook via Axinn Library (Hofstra login required). Hofstra now provides unlimited access to this title, so you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have any problems accessing it, but let me know.  Reading questions  TBA TBA  See also  Adriaans, Pieter. 2020. “Information,” in the Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 4: Biological Sexes</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/biological-sexes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 07:56:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/biological-sexes/</guid>
      <description>Reading  Griffiths, Paul. 2020. “Sex is Real.” Aeon. Richardson, Sarah S. 2022. “Sex Contextualism.” Philosophy, Theory, and Practice in Biology 14 (2). doi: https://doi.org/10.3998/ptpbio.2096  Reading questions  What conceptions of sex does Griffiths argue against? What conception of sex does Griffiths argue for? What is Griffiths&amp;rsquo;s argument for his conception of sex? Why are sex chromosomes not sufficient for biological sex? How does Griffiths argue that his conception of biological sex cannot be used to characterize sex in non-biological human institutions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 3: Evolution and Ethics</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/evolution-and-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 12:11:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/evolution-and-ethics/</guid>
      <description>Reading  Darwin, Charles. 1871. Descent of Man, or, Selection in Relation to Sex. short excerpt distributed in class. Wilson, E. O. 1975. Sociobiology: The New Synthesis. short excerpt distributed in class. Kitcher, Philip. 1993. “Four Ways of &amp;lsquo;Biologicizing&amp;rsquo; Ethics.” In In Mendel&amp;rsquo;s mirror: philosophical reflections on biology. Oxford University Press, 2003. Find the eBook through Axinn Library here. Godfrey-Smith, Peter. 2013. “Evolution and Social Behavior,” Chapter 8 of Philosophy of Biology, Princeton University Press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2: Darwin and Natural Selection</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/darwin-and-natural-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 16:57:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/darwin-and-natural-selection/</guid>
      <description>Reading  Darwin, Charles. 1859. The Origin of Species. First edition (of 6). Read Chapter 3. Then, read just up to page 10 in Chapter 4, and finally the final paragraph of Chapter 14 (on the last page). Available via Blackboard. Waters, C. Kenneth. 2003. “The Arguments in the Origin of Species.” In The Cambridge Companion to Darwin, edited by Gregory Radick and Jonathan Hodge, 116–139. Cambridge University Press. via Blackboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1: Before Natural Selection</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/before-natural-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 16:56:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi162/topics/before-natural-selection/</guid>
      <description>Reading  Aristotle, excerpts from Physics and Parts of Animals (about 350 BCE). Handout. Available through Blackboard &amp;gt; Course Documents.  Note: This is short but dense. Try to work through it carefully; see the reading questions below ↓.   William Smellie, “Of the Progressive Scale or Chain of Beings in the Universe” (1791). Available through Blackboard &amp;gt; Course Documents.  Note: This is an account of the relationships among all living things from the perspective of late-eighteenth century biology in England.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
